Is there anything nicer than a cooling ice cream on a hot summer's day?
还有什么比在炎热夏日里来一份清凉的冰淇淋更惬意的事吗？
This traditional treat is centuries old, but our tastes and consumer habits are evolving.
这种传统美食已有数百年历史，但我们的口味和消费习惯却在不断演变。
How is the ice cream production process changing, and who is driving this change?
冰淇淋的生产流程正发生着怎样的变化？又是谁在推动这些变化呢？
Making ice cream is a time-consuming process.
制作冰淇淋是一个耗时的过程。
While the recipe is simple – milk, sugar and fat, plus flavours and colours – ice cream has a complex chemistry.
尽管配方很简单——牛奶、糖、脂肪，再加上调味剂和色素——但冰淇淋的制作却涉及复杂的化学变化。
Getting the balance right between ice, fat and air is important if the ice cream is to have the right texture.
要让冰淇淋拥有恰到好处的口感，关键在于平衡好冰、脂肪和空气三者的比例。
To achieve this, the ingredients need to be mixed and heated, then cooled and frozen – a process that takes time and uses a lot of energy.
为了达到这个效果，原料需要经过混合、加热，再冷却、冷冻，整个过程既耗时又耗能。
Designers and engineers are working to improve the production process with new specialised equipment to make it increasingly automated.
设计师和工程师们正研发新型专业设备来改进生产流程，使其自动化程度越来越高。
For now, however, even with the help of robots and 3D printers, it can take up to two years from testing a new frozen dessert product to it being available to consumers.
不过目前，即便有机器人和3D打印机的助力，一款新冷冻甜品从测试到面向消费者上市，也可能需要长达两年的时间。
And demand is only going up.
冰淇淋的需求还在持续增长。
According to the food packaging company Tetra Pak, more than 25 billion litres of ice cream were eaten worldwide in 2021.
据利乐食品包装公司的数据显示，2021年全球冰淇淋的消费量超过250亿升。
While the US and China are the biggest consumers, data from NielsenIQ shows that people in the UK bought 28% more ice cream during the UK's record-breaking summer compared to a year earlier.
美国和中国是最大的消费市场，而尼尔森IQ的数据表明，在英国创纪录高温的那个夏天，人们购买的冰淇淋数量与去年同时期相比增长了28%。
Clearly, rising temperatures can explain why some people are buying more ice cream, but it's not the only explanation.
显然，气温上升是冰淇淋销量增加的原因之一，但这并非唯一的因素。
The pandemic has seen people reaching for pleasures they can enjoy at home, which include eating indulgent foods.
疫情期间，人们更倾向于寻求可以在家享受的乐趣，吃些解馋的美食便是其中之一。
And worries about the cost-of-living crisis could have a similar effect, as even a premium ice cream is an affordable treat.
而对生活成本危机的担忧也可能产生类似的影响，因为即便是高端冰淇淋，也算得上是一种价格亲民的享受。
So, what new things can we expect on a stick or in a cone?
那么，未来我们能在冰淇淋棒或蛋筒里吃到些什么新花样呢？
Consumers of all ages buy ice cream, but it is millennial consumers who are driving interest in more original flavours, including spices.
各个年龄段的消费者都会购买冰淇淋，但正是千禧一代消费者推动了人们对更具创意的口味的兴趣，包括添加香料的冰淇淋。
Dairy still dominates, but plant-based ice cream, sorbets and low-calorie choices are a growing part of the frozen dessert market.
乳制品冰淇淋仍占据主导地位，但植物基冰淇淋、果汁冰沙和低热量冰淇淋在冷冻甜品市场的占比正不断提升。
But, according to Elsebeth Baungaard, portfolio manager at Tetra Pak, the next global trend will be less about innovation and more about portion size.
不过，利乐公司的投资组合经理埃尔斯贝思·邦高指出，下一个全球趋势将不再侧重于创新，而是聚焦分量。
"I'm sorry to say it's simply shrinking", she says. "But the quality will be higher."
“很遗憾地说，分量确实在变小，”她表示，“但品质会变得更高。”